sugarforge.org 2017-02-01

# SugarCRM Inc. Privacy Policy | SugarCRM.com

SugarCRM Inc. and the subsidiaries we own or control worldwide (collectively, "SugarCRM") respect your privacy. This privacy policy (the "Policy") explains how SugarCRM collects and uses data collected from you, including personal information, through (i) our publicly available websites (the "Sites"), and (ii) the SugarCRM mobile and other add-on applications (e.g., SugarCRM for iPhone, SugarCRM for Android, etc.) ("Apps") and other related services on which we post a direct link to this Policy (together with Apps, the "Services"). This Policy does not cover any other data collection or processing, including without limitation, the data we host for our registered customers. If you purchase or download our solutions, the data that you (and your customers) submit as you use our solutions will be governed by the applicable SugarCRM agreement, and as required by law.

**How We Collect Information**

_Directly from You_

We collect personal information from you when you interact with our Sites or use our Services. For example, we collect personal information from you when you purchase our products, complete a profile, register with us, participate in surveys, register for an event, apply for a job, download a white paper, participate in a webcast, complete questionnaires or contests, contact us with questions or comments, request information such as a newsletter, provide us with feedback, or voluntarily post in blogs, chat rooms, forums or messages boards available from the Sites. The type of information that we collect from you depends upon your interaction with our Sites and Services, but may include, your contact information such as your name, address, email address and phone number, username, password, language choice, time zone, employment title and company information, credit card information or other payment information, tax identification number and reseller identification number, and other personal information that you actively submit to us.

_From Third Parties_

We may collect personal information about you from our third party affiliates or partner companies and from marketing or advertising companies that provide us with such information as a part of their relationship with us. We may combine this with information that we already have collected about you.

_Automatically Through our Site_

We use various tracking technologies to collect and store information from you when you use our Services, such as your IP address, browser type, browser language, operating system, device type, referring site (site you visited before coming to our site), date and time of visit, URL and page metadata, installation data (such as the operating system type and application version), and information such as crashes, system activity and hardware settings. We may also automatically collect and store certain information in activity logs such as: details of how you used our Sites and Services, your search queries, and your IP address. Please see our section entitled "Cookies and Other Tracking Devices" below for additional information.

_Information Collected Through our Apps_

We may collect clickstream data and other related information about your use of our Apps. We use this information to understand how you use our Apps, for service improvement, troubleshooting and as described in this Policy.

**How We Use Your Information**

We use information we collect to conduct our business and improve our Sites and Services, develop new products and services, provide information and support, to better understand your needs and interests, personalize communications and advertising, and generally promote a quality experience for you. For example, we may use your information, including your personal information, to:

  * Communicate, interact and build our relationship with you;
  * Customize the content, products and services that are offered to you;
  * Contact you with information about SugarCRM and affiliated third-parties;
  * Process, fulfill and follow up on transactions and requests for products, services, support, and information;
  * Verify your authority to enter and use our Services;
  * Engage in market research and analysis;
  * Measure, analyze and improve our products and services, the effectiveness of our websites, and our advertising and marketing;
  * Consider your employment application;
  * Comply with legal requirements;
  * Provide targeting advertising, including the use of re-targeting technology;
  * Send you marketing materials, for example, via email, including our newsletter, and to notify you about products and services that we believe would be of interest to you; or
  * Deter, detect, and prevent fraud and other prohibited or illegal activities.

We may link information we collect from multiple sources to provide better service to you and to improve our products and services.

**How We Share and Disclose Your Information**

We do not sell your personal information with third parties for their own marketing purposes. We may share or disclose your personal information as follows:

  * To affiliated and unaffiliated service providers for the sole purpose of enabling them to provide services to us in connection with providing our Services to you;
  * Based on a good faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person, violation of our Policy, as evidence in litigation in which we are involved, or to otherwise protect the rights or safety of any person or entity;
  * Based on a good-faith belief that disclosure is necessary to respond to judicial process, valid government inquiry, or is otherwise required by law;
  * If we are acquired by or merged with another entity, if all or part of our assets are acquired, or in response to a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer your information to the acquiring entity;
  * When posted by you or an authorized third-party, to our wikis, forums, blogs, message boards, chat rooms and other social networking environments or Sites;
  * We also may share aggregate or non-personally identifiable data about users with third parties for marketing, advertising, research, analytics or similar purposes; and
  * To other third parties for purposes you have allowed or consented to.

**Access and Opt-Out**

You may review and update your contact information by accessing and modifying the information in your account or by submitting a request to SugarCRM at [webmaster@sugarcrm.com](mailto:webmaster@sugarcrm.com).

If you choose not to receive SugarCRM sent emails or newsletters, you can opt-out or unsubscribe by emailing [contact@sugarcrm.com](mailto:contact@sugarcrm.com), by following the opt-out instructions in the email or newsletter, or by sending mail to SugarCRM Inc., 10050 N. Wolfe Rd. SW2-130, Cupertino CA 95014, USA or call +1 408.454.6900.

Please note that while SugarCRM offers you some control over marketing communication, certain transactional, relationship, and legally required communications will not be affected by the choices you have made about marketing communications.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Devices**

We use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of our Sites and Services.

**_Cookies:_** Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, storing your preferences, and generally improving your experience on our Sites. Cookies make the interaction between you and the Sites faster and easier.

We use cookies to improve your user experience by enabling our Sites to 'remember' you, either for the duration of your visit (using a "session cookie") or for repeat visits (using a "persistent cookie"). SugarCRM uses both session cookies and persistent cookies when you access our Sites. Session cookies expire and no longer have any effect when you log out of your account or close your browser. Persistent cookies remain on your browser until you erase them or they expire.

You may encounter cookies or pixel tags on websites that we do not control. For example, if you view a web page created by a third party or use an application developed by a third party, there may be a cookie or pixel tag placed by the web page or application. Likewise, these third parties may place cookies or pixel tags that are not subject to our control and this Policy does not cover their use.

How Do I Disable Cookies? Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not function.

**_Web Beacons:_** We may use "web beacons" (electronic images also known as pixel tags or clear gifs) to recognize a cookie on your computer when you view or act upon a web page, an advertisement that we've placed on a third-party web page, or an email or other electronic communication that we've sent.

**_Local Storage Objects ("LSOs"):_** We also use Local Shared Objects (LSO), sometimes referred to as "Flash" cookies. Use of Local Shared Objects can help prevent fraud and can support our Sites. Flash LSOs are different from browser cookies because of the amount and type of data stored. Typically, you cannot control, delete, or disable the acceptance of Flash LSOs through your web browser. For more information on Flash LSOs, or to learn how to manage your settings for Flash LSOs, go to the Adobe Flash Player Help Page, choose "Global Storage Settings Panel" and follow the instructions. To see the Flash LSOs currently on your computer, choose "Website Storage Settings Panel" and follow the instructions to review and, if you choose, to delete any specific Flash LSO.

**_Other Tracking Technologies:_** We may also collect usage and performance data through our Apps using various platform specific- tracking technologies applicable to the Apps.

**_Do Not Track:_** Our Sites do not respond to web browser “do not track” signals or other mechanisms. If, in the future, we create a program or protocol to respond to such web browser signals, we will inform you and share details of how it works.

**Third Parties**

SugarCRM may allow certain companies, such as analytics partners, advertisers, application developers and ad networks, to use cookies, web beacons, LSOs and other tracking technologies on the Sites and Services as described below.

**_Analytics:_** SugarCRM uses a variety of third-party services to help us understand the use of our Sites and Services, such as Google Analytics. These third-party service providers may collect information sent by your browser or mobile device, such as cookies or your IP address.

For example, the information generated by the cookie and other platform-specific technology about your use of our Services (including your Internet protocol ("IP") address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Sites, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf.

**_Advertising:_** We use third parties such as network advertisers and analytics providers to assist us in displaying advertisements on our Sites and on third party websites. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to our Sites as well as other websites. In cases of re-targeting technology, third party ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may put cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), Flash LSOs and other technologies on your computer to collect information about your interests. This provides our website visitors with advertising displays or text ads, that most likely match their product and information interests and enables us and the network advertisers to measure the effectiveness of the ads.

You may opt-out of many third party ad networks. To learn more about this, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) at [www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) (NAI) or the Digital Advertising Alliance at [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) (DAA). Opting out of one or more NAI member or DAA member networks (many of which will be the same) only means that those members no longer will deliver targeted content or ads to you. It does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content or ads on our Site or other websites.

**User Generated Content**

We may collect personal information about you when you voluntarily post in blogs, chat rooms, forums or message boards available from the Sites. All of the information that you post will be available to all visitors to our Sites. SugarCRM is not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. We cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law or your personal privacy.

**Notice to Non-U.S. Persons**

If you choose to provide us with information, including personal information, you understand that we are transferring it to SugarCRM's locations and systems in the United States or to the locations and systems of SugarCRM's service providers around the world.

**Links to Third Party Site(s) and Applications**

The Sites provide links to third party websites or resources (e.g. applications) over which SugarCRM does not have control. Such links do not constitute an endorsement by SugarCRM and SugarCRM does not control the content or privacy policies or practices of such sites. Any access to and use of such linked websites or any resources available on our Sites is not governed by this Policy, but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those third parties' websites.

**Security**

Transmissions over the Internet are never 100% secure or error-free. SugarCRM employs procedural and technological measures that are reasonably designed to help protect personal information from loss, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

**Children's Privacy**

SugarCRM recognizes the privacy interests of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests. This Site is not intended for children under the age of 13. SugarCRM does not target this Site to children under 13. SugarCRM does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

**US-EU Safe Harbor Privacy Principles**

The U.S.-European Union Safe Harbor program addresses the collection, protection, storage, transfer, use and other processing of data transferred from the European Economic Area to the United States. While SugarCRM is not currently registered with the Safe Harbor program, SugarCRM is nonetheless committed to applying the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles in providing its products and services.

**Our Collection of Usage Data Through Our Products**

_Usage Data_. In the course of providing you with the SugarCRM product and services, we may collect, use, process and store Usage Data in order to  create and compile anonymized, aggregated datasets and/or statistics about the products or services for the following purposes: (a) to maintain and improve the performance and integrity of SugarCRM products or services, (b) to understand which SugarCRM products or services are most commonly deployed and preferred by customers and how customers interact with SugarCRM products or services, (c) to identify the types of SugarCRM products or services that may require additional maintenance or support, and (d) to comply with regulatory, legislative and/or contractual requirements; provided in each case that such aggregated datasets and statistics will not enable you or any living individual to be identified.

_Web Analytics._ As one means of collecting Usage Data, we use third party web analytics tools (such as Google Analytics) that serve cookies or similar tracking technologies through our products and services, on end user devices, to collect anonymous Usage Data for the purposes described above. You are responsible for informing your end users about our use of such web analytics tools in connection with the products and related services.

_Critical Control Software._ The Sugar product also includes Critical Control Software that regularly transmits certain Usage Data to us and, if applicable, an authorized partner, to verify compliance with the terms of the applicable agreement and to improve the SugarCRM products and services

“Usage Data” means diagnostic and usage related content from the computer, mobile phone or other devices your users use to access the SugarCRM product and may include, but is not limited to, IP addresses, internet service, location, type of browser and modules that are used and/or accessed, licensing, system and service performance data. Usage Data does not, however, include Your Data.

"Your Data" means any data, information or material stored by you in the SugarCRM product.

“Critical Control Software" means software with functionality that reports the number of authorized subscription users, and provides us (and Authorized Partners, where applicable) with the ability to monitor certain usage of the product.

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to change, modify, add or remove portions of this statement from time to time and in our sole discretion, but will alert you that changes have been made by indicating on the statement the date it was last updated. Your continued access to the Sites and Services will indicate your acceptance of our updated Policy. We recommend that users revisit this statement on occasion to learn of any changes.

**Contact Us**

Please contact us by writing to us at: [contact@sugarcrm.com](mailto:contact@sugarcrm.com) or SugarCRM Inc., 10050 N. Wolfe Rd. SW2-130, Cupertino CA 95014, USA, c/o General Counsel if you have any questions regarding this Policy.

Last Update: August 2016
